<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Wine | x2q dot net]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/categories/wine/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.x2q.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-05T12:17:22+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.x2q.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[x2q]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[x2q@x2q.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Howto Install Office 2010 using Wine]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/04/10/howto-install-office-2010-using-wine/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-10T19:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/04/10/howto-install-office-2010-using-wine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft Office 2010 is the most recent version of the Microsoft Office
productivity suite. Formerly known as Office 14 in the initial stages of
its beta cycle, it was released to customers in 2010.</p>

<p>This howto assume that you got an ISO image of the installation media.</p>

<p>If you are on Debian/Ubuntu you can install wine, winetricks, and winbind using
<code>
sudo apt-get install wine1.5 winetricks winbind
</code></p>

<p>In order to install you'll need the following native Microsoft Windows libraries (dll files)
<code>
WINEARCH=win32 winetricks riched20 winhttp
</code></p>

<p>Then mount and install
<code>
sudo mount -o loop -o unhide Microsoft-Office-2010.iso /mnt
WINEARCH=win32 wine /mnt/setup.exe
</code></p>

<p>Test Excel
<code>
WINEARCH=win32 wine ~/.wine/drive_c/Program\ Files/Microsoft\ Office/Office14/EXCEL.EXE
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Howto run Netflix on Ubuntu Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/02/23/howto-run-netflix-on-ubuntu-linux/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-23T22:52:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/02/23/howto-run-netflix-on-ubuntu-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Netflix is finally working on Linux - not native, but with a patched Wine build,
you can now use Netflix under Linux.</p>

<p>For those who are not familiar with Netflix, it is an American provider of
on-demand Internet streaming media available to both North and South America,
the Caribbean, United Kingdom, Ireland, Sweden, Denmark, Norway, Finland.</p>

<h2>How to install</h2>

<pre><code>  $ sudo apt-add-repository ppa:ehoover/compholio
  $ sudo apt-get update
  $ sudo apt-get install netflix-desktop
</code></pre>

<p>The Netflix Desktop package installs all of the components necessary to run Netflix
Watch Instantly under Wine, including the Windows version of Mozilla Firefox and
Microsoft Silverlight v4. The package also includes some convience
settings to integrate Netflix into Firefox in such a way that everything feels
like a native application.</p>

<h2>Run Netflix</h2>

<p>You can launch the Netflix Desktop web app through desktop Dash menu.
The Netflix Desktop application runs in full screen, but you can exit full
screen mode by pressing F11 (just like any other browser).</p>

<h2>Use it for websites that require Silverlight / PlayReady DRM</h2>

<p>Start the Netflix Desktop web app and then press F11 (to exit full screen mode),
then press ALT + v and then the menu occurs, now enable the Menu Bar and
Navigation Toolbar.</p>

<p>Now you are able to navigate to
<a href="http://web.sldrm.video.msn.com/">http://web.sldrm.video.msn.com/</a> or
<a href="http://www.filmstriben.dk/">http://www.filmstriben.dk/</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
