<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Debian | x2q dot net]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/categories/debian/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.x2q.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-05T14:17:19+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.x2q.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[x2q]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[x2q@x2q.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Howto: Install MariaDB on Debian 7/Wheezy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/05/05/howto-install-mariadb-on-debian-7-slash-wheezy/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-05T10:04:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/05/05/howto-install-mariadb-on-debian-7-slash-wheezy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.mariadb.org">MariaDB</a> is a fork of <a href="http://www.mysql.com">MySQL</a>, which is true open source and community
maintained. MariaDB is a binary drop in <a href="https://kb.askmonty.org/en/mariadb-versus-mysql-compatibility/">replacement</a> for MySQL. It includes
the XtraDB storage engine as a replacement for InnoDB. Its lead developer is
<a href="http://askmonty.org/">Michael Widenius</a> (also known as "Monty"), the founder of MySQL.</p>

<p>Recently, many popular Linux distributions replaced MySQL with MariaDB as
default database server. Fedora <a href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Features/ReplaceMySQLwithMariaDB">since version 19</a>, Archlinux <a href="https://www.archlinux.org/news/mariadb-replaces-mysql-in-repositories/">since March
2013</a> and <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/oracle-who-fedora-and-opensuse-will-replace-mysql-with-mariadb-7000010640/">OpenSuse</a>. Moreover Wikipedia <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/wikipedia-moving-from-mysql-to-mariadb-7000008912/">moved</a> to MariaDB and
Mozilla <a href="http://blog.mozilla.org/it/2013/01/17/mysql-5-1-vs-mysql-5-5-floats-doubles-and-scientific-notation/">also uses</a> MariaDB.</p>

<p>Famous distributions often used in server environments such as Debian and
Centos have not replaced MySQL with MariaDB yet, but they'll probaly soon
migrate as well.</p>

<h2>Why switch to MariaDB</h2>

<p>Well, MySQL development has basically stopped, since Oracle acquired MySQL,
whereas the MariaDB development is progessing at full speed.</p>

<p>Performance and licensing are the often the most predominant reasons to make a
switch from MySQL to MariaDB.</p>

<p>Regarding performance - here is what Wikipedia experienced, when they compared
MariaDB to the <a href="https://launchpad.net/mysqlatfacebook/51">Facebook fork of MySQL 5.1</a>.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Many query types were 4-15% faster with MariaDB 5.5.30<br/>under production load, a few were 5% slower, and nothing<br/>appeared aberrant beyond those bounds.</p><footer><strong>Asher Feldman</strong> <cite><a href='http://blog.wikimedia.org/2013/04/22/wikipedia-adopts-mariadb/'>Wikipedia Adopts MariaDB</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<h2>Install MariaDB on Debian Wheeze</h2>

<p>MariaDB packages are not yet available in official Debian repositories. MariaDB
provides repositories for almost every popular os here:</p>

<p><a href="https://downloads.mariadb.org/mariadb/repositories">https://downloads.mariadb.org/mariadb/repositories/</a></p>

<p>Add the following to your <code>/etc/apt/sources.list</code></p>

<p><code>
deb http://ftp.osuosl.org/pub/mariadb/repo/5.5/debian wheezy main
</code></p>

<p>and then</p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-key adv --recv-keys --keyserver keyserver.ubuntu.com 0xcbcb082a1bb943db
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install mariadb-server-5.5 libmysqlclient18=5.5.30-mariadb1~wheezy
</code></p>

<p>The <strong>libmysqlclient18=5.5.30-mariadb1~wheezy</strong> is needed as a work-around to this
<a href="https://mariadb.atlassian.net/browse/MDEV-3882">bug</a>.</p>

<p>This should result is something like this...</p>

<p><code>
Reading package lists... Done
Building dependency tree       
Reading state information... Done
The following extra packages will be installed:
  libaio1 libdbd-mysql-perl libdbi-perl libhtml-template-perl libmariadbclient18 libnet-daemon-perl libplrpc-perl mariadb-client-5.5
  mariadb-client-core-5.5 mariadb-common mariadb-server-core-5.5 mysql-common psmisc
Suggested packages:
  libipc-sharedcache-perl tinyca mailx mariadb-test
The following NEW packages will be installed:
  libaio1 libdbd-mysql-perl libdbi-perl libhtml-template-perl libmariadbclient18 libmysqlclient18 libnet-daemon-perl libplrpc-perl
  mariadb-client-5.5 mariadb-client-core-5.5 mariadb-common mariadb-server-5.5 mariadb-server-core-5.5 mysql-common psmisc
0 upgraded, 15 newly installed, 0 to remove and 0 not upgraded.
Need to get 32.3 MB of archives.
After this operation, 111 MB of additional disk space will be used.
Do you want to continue [Y/n]?
</code></p>

<p>You are now ready to use MariaDB.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu: Optimize for speed]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/04/21/ubuntu-optimize-for-speed/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-21T21:20:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/04/21/ubuntu-optimize-for-speed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This easy little guide will help you with simple optimization tips for speeding
up Ubuntu (12.04, 12.10, and 13.04) and other Ubuntu-based systems such as Linux
Mint. The tips come in very handy for those using older computers with low RAM
who need to boost their computer for better speed and performance and if you are
just want a really fast and snappy computer on some regular hardware.</p>

<h2>Removing Ubuntu One client</h2>

<p>Saves >100 MB ram.</p>

<p>The following steps can be followed to completely remove the Ubuntu One client
software.</p>

<p><code>
killall ubuntuone-login ubuntuone-preferences ubuntuone-syncdaemon
sudo rm -rf ~/.local/share/ubuntuone
rm -rf ~/.cache/ubuntuone
rm -rf ~/.config/ubuntuone
rm ~/Ubuntu\ One
</code></p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get purge ubuntuone-client python-ubuntuone-storage*
</code></p>

<h2>Remove unused Unity lenses</h2>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get purge \
unity-lens-friends \
unity-lens-music \
unity-lens-photos \
unity-lens-shopping \
unity-lens-video \
unity-lens-radios
</code></p>

<h2>Optimize mount options</h2>

<p>Ubuntu use the relatime flag for updating file metadata when files are accessed.
All these updates involve writes to the disk. We can avoid this with the
<code>noatime</code> and <code>nodiratime</code> parameters. This means that access time to files and
directories won't be tracked at all.</p>

<h2>Use tmpfs for /tmp and /var etc.</h2>

<p>Add a section like this tmpfs section to <code>/etc/fstab</code></p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/5459544.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code></code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<h2>Move browser cache to tmpfs</h2>

<p><code>
rm -rf ~/.cache/google-chrome
ln -s /tmp ~/.cache/google-chrome
</code></p>

<h2>Move browser profile to memory using Profile-sync-daemon</h2>

<p><a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Profile-sync-daemon">Profile-sync-daemon
(psd)</a> is a diminutive
pseudo-daemon designed to manage your browser's profile in tmpfs and to
periodically sync it back to your physical disc (HDD/SSD). This is accomplished
via a symlinking step and an innovative use of rsync to maintain back-up and
synchronization between the two. One of the major design goals of psd is a
completely transparent user experience.</p>

<p>Running this daemon is beneficial for two reasons:
* Reduced wear to physical discs
* Speed</p>

<p><code>
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:graysky/utils
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install profile-sync-daemon
</code></p>

<p>Adjust <code>/etc/psd.conf</code> to match your setup and then restart the
Profile-sync-daemon. Your browser(s) needs to be closed before restart of the
Profile-sync-daemon.</p>

<p><code>
sudo /etc/init.d/psd restart
</code></p>

<h2>Remove orphaned libraries</h2>

<p>Over time most Ubuntu/Debian installations acquire packages which are no longer
required - they've just been pulled in to satisfy dependencies of software
you've since removed - deborphan package is probably the simplest way to get rid
of orphaned and unused packages.</p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install deborphan
sudo apt-get remove --purge `deborphan`; sudo apt-get autoremove
</code></p>

<h2>Clean browsers cache etc and vacuum browser databases.</h2>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install bleachbit
bleachbit -c `bleachbit -l | grep cache`
bleachbit -c `bleachbit -l | grep tmp`
bleachbit -c `bleachbit -l | grep vacuum`
</code></p>

<h2>Clean rotated log files</h2>

<p><code>
sudo bleachbit -c system.rotated_logs
</code></p>

<h2>Clean temp and backup files</h2>

<p>First do a dry-run and check that everything is good to go.
<code>
bleachbit -p deepscan.*
</code></p>

<p>and then do the real one
<code>
bleachbit -c deepscan.*
</code></p>

<h2>Disable unnecessary services and applications</h2>

<p>Use BUM, which is a runlevel configuration tool with GUI that allows Ubuntu
users to edit and configure init services that are started when the system is
booting up or restarting. With this tool, you will be displayed with all
running and disabled services in which you can turn them on/off.</p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install bum
sudo bum
</code></p>

<p>To remove applications from startup go to <code>Dash</code> > and type <code>Startup Applications</code>.</p>

<p><img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/-F4MJSlus31U/UXo8S6sRcKI/AAAAAAAAKRc/MbftYfyzMRo/ubuntu-startup-application-preferences.png"></p>

<p>Disable automatic startup of any services that are not needed (or even remove
the package completely).</p>

<h2>Increases performance using zRam</h2>

<p><a href="https://code.google.com/p/compcache/">zRam</a> is a module of the Linux kernel. It
was previously called “compcache”. zRam increases performance by avoiding paging
on disk and instead uses a compressed block device in RAM in which paging takes
place until it is necessary to use the swap space on the hard disk drive. Since
using RAM is faster than using disks, zRam allows Linux to make more use of RAM
when swapping/paging is required, especially on older computers with less RAM
installed.</p>

<p>FYI: <a href="http://www.chromestory.com/2013/03/google-enabling-zram-for-chrome-os-by-default/">Google uses zRAM for Chrome OS</a></p>

<p>Enable zRam on Ubuntu:</p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install zram-config
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Howto install memcached gem on Ubuntu/Debian]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/04/16/howto-install-memcached-gem-on-ubuntu-slash-debian/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-16T15:54:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/04/16/howto-install-memcached-gem-on-ubuntu-slash-debian</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Memcached is a general-purpose distributed memory caching system used by many
sites around. It is often used to speed up dynamic database-driven websites by
caching data and objects in RAM to reduce the number of times an external data
source (such as a database or API) must be read. Memcached runs on Unix, Linux,
Windows and Mac OS X.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://rubygems.org/gems/memcached">memcached gem</a> requires the following
development libraries to be installed</p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install libmemcached-dev libsasl2-dev
</code></p>

<p>and then</p>

<p><code>
sudo gem install memcached
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Howto Install Office 2010 using Wine]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/04/10/howto-install-office-2010-using-wine/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-10T19:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/04/10/howto-install-office-2010-using-wine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft Office 2010 is the most recent version of the Microsoft Office
productivity suite. Formerly known as Office 14 in the initial stages of
its beta cycle, it was released to customers in 2010.</p>

<p>This howto assume that you got an ISO image of the installation media.</p>

<p>If you are on Debian/Ubuntu you can install wine, winetricks, and winbind using
<code>
sudo apt-get install wine1.5 winetricks winbind
</code></p>

<p>In order to install you'll need the following native Microsoft Windows libraries (dll files)
<code>
WINEARCH=win32 winetricks riched20 winhttp
</code></p>

<p>Then mount and install
<code>
sudo mount -o loop -o unhide Microsoft-Office-2010.iso /mnt
WINEARCH=win32 wine /mnt/setup.exe
</code></p>

<p>Test Excel
<code>
WINEARCH=win32 wine ~/.wine/drive_c/Program\ Files/Microsoft\ Office/Office14/EXCEL.EXE
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Howto Backup WD MyBook Live to Amazon S3 and Glacier]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/02/24/howto-backup-wd-mybook-live-to-amazon-s3-and-glacier/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T14:25:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/02/24/howto-backup-wd-mybook-live-to-amazon-s3-and-glacier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I helped a <a href="http://www.winniemethmann.com/">photographer</a> to backup a large photo collection (several
terabytes) from a <a href="http://www.wdc.com/">Western Digital (WD)</a> personal NAS
MyBook Live.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_Digital_My_Book">My Book Live Edition
NAS</a> was released by
Western Digital in 2011. They range in storage capacity from 1 to 4 TB. My Book
Live features a 1 GHz ARM processor, 256 MB of RAM, and 1000 Mbit/s ethernet
connectivity. Contrary to previous My Book Live versions it now features a
fully fledged <a href="http://www.debian.org/">Debian linux distribution</a>, whichs makes
the My Book Live easy to customize and adapt to different needs.</p>

<h2>Backup your My Book Live to Amazon S3 and Glacier</h2>

<p>This assumes that you got SSH access to your My Book Live. If you haven't got
SSH, then do the following to enable SSH access.</p>

<h3>Enable SSH via hidden menu on WD My Book Live</h3>

<p>Go to <a href="http://mybooklive/UI/ssh">http://mybooklive/UI/ssh</a> (case sensitive)
replace "mybooklive" if you have renamed your My Book Live to something else,
or replace it with its IP address. It's a hidden UI menu to enable SSH.</p>

<p>Now you are able to ssh to your My Book Live via
<a href="http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/">putty</a> or another ssh
client.</p>

<h3>Install the backup tool Duplicity etc.</h3>

<pre><code>  $ apt-get install python-boto duplicity util-linux trickle
</code></pre>

<p>I used the following Bash script as a cron job. The script features:</p>

<ul>
<li>exclusive locking using flock - ensures that only instance is actice at the time. This is useful, when your backup might run for several days.</li>
<li>bandwidth / upload limit using trickle.</li>
<li>custom temp and cache folders - this is required on a WD My Book Live as it got limited space on the root file system</li>
</ul>


<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/5024054.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code></code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Now it is time to make the script run every night. Edit your crontab:</p>

<pre><code>    $ crontab -e
</code></pre>

<p>Add the following line</p>

<pre><code>    # m h  dom mon dow   command 
    42  22  *   *   *    /root/wd-live-s3-backup.sh
</code></pre>

<p>Then be sure to check your log files and do restore to check that everything is
good.</p>

<h3>Adjust S3 lifecycle rule</h3>

<p>Amazon supports archiving of Amazon S3 Data to Amazon Glacier using lifecycle rules.</p>

<p>I use the following lifecycle rule for Amazon S3 and Glacier.</p>

<p><img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/-9vxrov_LRmM/UXjf1037BII/AAAAAAAAKL4/tFJy90mQAjM/w677/s3-glacier-lifecycle-rules.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
