<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Review | x2q dot net]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/categories/review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.x2q.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-06T15:02:58+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.x2q.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[x2q]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[x2q@x2q.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 12.10 Review: Nearly perfect]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/2012/10/16/ubuntu-12-dot-10-review-nearly-perfect/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-16T12:17:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.x2q.net/blog/2012/10/16/ubuntu-12-dot-10-review-nearly-perfect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I last upgraded to <a href="http://www.ubuntu.com/">Ubuntu 12.04</a>, I was quite disappointed. Mostly because it was a LTS release and though you do not expect buggy and unpolished components.</p>

<p>Back to Ubuntu 12.10.</p>

<h2>Installation</h2>

<p>The installation is simple and for the first time ever my girlfriend was able to install Ubuntu without my support. During the installation she even mentioned that is was incredible easy and straight forward.</p>

<p>The best thing about the installation is the fact that you don't waste time during the installation process. The installer simply starts the installation right after you've chosen the partition scheme and then while it installs you are asked for additional user details, username, password, timezone etc.</p>

<p>All in all quite efficient and almost as polished as the Mac installer. And a lot faster than the Windows installer.</p>

<h2>Bootup &amp; Boot time</h2>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='tested on a modern SSD I ended up with a boot time of ~10 seconds'>
Ubuntu 12.10 feels faster compared to Ubuntu 12.04. But in essence boot time shouldn't be more than 5 seconds and Ubuntu 12.10 is still far from this, when using a regular disk drive, but when tested on a modern SSD I ended up with a boot time of ~10 seconds.
</span></p>

<p>Compared to Mac OS, Ubuntu still got a few flaws. For example random text messages occurs randomly during boot and shutdown from time to time. Not a problem as a such, but Mr. Jobs would never accepted a product release with this kind of unpolished user experience. Who said Apple Maps.</p>

<h2>The Desktop</h2>

<p>The overall look and feel is simply great, but the new sponsored items in the dash is simply annoying and leaves the desktop area as a cluttered space. However with the annoying sponsored Amazon content uninstalled the Ubuntu desktop is a pleasure. It is fast and quite responsive, don't get me wrong there is still room for improvements.</p>

<p><img src="http://static.x2q.net/Ubuntu-12.10-Screenshot-2012-10-16-800x.jpg"></p>

<p>The annoying shopping unity lens can be removed by:</p>

<pre><code>sudo apt-get install unity-lens-shopping
</code></pre>

<p>The Mac inspired reworked <code>System Settings</code> is really a step in the right direction. It is pleasant to use, however why aren't all configuration items shown, e.g. <code>Desktop Sharing</code>?</p>

<h2>Behind the Scenes</h2>

<p>Looking into the machine room with <code>ps aux</code> and <code>top</code> was a mixed experience.</p>

<pre><code>RSS     COMMAND
40m     /usr/bin/python /usr/lib/ubuntuone-client/ubuntuone-syncdaemon
30m     /usr/bin/python3 /usr/lib/unity-lens-photos/unity-lens-photos
19m     /usr/bin/python /usr/lib/unity-scope-video-remote/unity-scope-video-remote
16m     /usr/bin/python /usr/lib/unity-lens-video/unity-lens-video
13m     update-notifier
 8m     /usr/lib/evolution/evolution-source-registry
 7m     /usr/lib/gwibber/unity-gwibber-daemon
 4m     /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/deja-dup/deja-dup-monitor
</code></pre>

<p>All in all there is a lot processes - most of them are needed, but a significant number of the processes are simply not needed. The ubuntuone-syncdaemon is running even when it is not configured yet and the same for the deja-dup-monitor.</p>

<p>The update-notifier is running constantly. Personally, I think that the unity-lenses are consuming quite a bit memory, even though memory is cheap today.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Ubuntu 12.10 is yet another step in the right direction. It is nearly perfect, when the cluttered sponsor content unity-lenses, misc memory hungry processes, and processes slowing bootup are uninstalled.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Logitech Squeezebox Touch and SUMOH TinyAmp S60]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/2010/08/31/review-logitech-squeezebox-touch-sumoh-tinyamp-s60/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-31T20:29:34+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.x2q.net/blog/2010/08/31/review-logitech-squeezebox-touch-sumoh-tinyamp-s60</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Logitech Squeezebox Touch</h2>

<p><img src="http://static.x2q.net/Logitech-Squeezebox-Touch.jpg" title="" ></p>

<p>Squeezebox Touch is equipped with a 4.3 inch touch color screen. The Touch can be operated directly by clicking on menus, as it can be operated with the included infrared <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Remote_control">remote control</a>, and of course, is compatible with the Squeezebox Controller. When Touch is controlled by infrared remote control, enlarged the font on the display automatically, so it can be read at greater distances. Squeezebox Touch can also be operated with e.g. an iPod Touch or <a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone">iPhone</a>.</p>

<h3>Light Sensor Automatically Adjusts Display Brightness</h3>

<p>The Touch is equipped with a light sensor that automatically adjusts display brightness to ambient light level. The Touch also has an infrared motion sensor, which enables the Touch to wake up when you approach it. The Touch can be powered from the digital amplifier directly from the SUMOH TinyAmp S60.</p>

<h3>High Definition Audio</h3>

<p>Squeezebox Touch is equipped with a DAC that supports playback of files in 24 bit/96 kHz resolution. Playback can be done from Mac, PC or different NAS servers, but the Squeezebox Touch also has built-in USB port and SD slot. You can play music from both various USB drives and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Digital">SD cards</a>, just like you on the screen can display images from same.</p>

<h2>SUMOH TinyAmp S60</h2>

<p>Combined with SUMOH TinyAmp S60 the sound quality is absolutely fair above average. I think most of the high quality can be explained by the lack of analog involvement - the only analog step if the is the output from the amplifier - the rest is pure digital (keep in mind that some recordings might involve analog steps as well).</p>

<p>Sumoh TinyAmp S60 is a 100% digital amplifier, directly designed for use with the Logitech Squeezebox, or other similar digital players. Volume adjusted from Squeezebox having variable digital outputs, or from another digital source with variable output. The amplifier turns on and off itself, depending on if there is any signal from the Squeezebox digital output. Very fancy ;-)</p>

<p><img src="http://static.x2q.net/SUMOH-TinyAmp-S60.jpg"></p>

<h2>Based on Texas Instruments</h2>

<p>Based on PurePathTM Digital from Texas Instruments and an ideal partner for the Squeezebox and <a href="http://www.apple.com">Apple</a> <a href="http://www.apple.com/wifi">Airport Express</a>
The amplifier is based on the latest technology from Texas Instruments, PurePathTM Digital, and is the only 100% digital amplifier in the world in its price range. The technology is also used in much more expensive amplifiers. TinyAmp may be very cheap, but do not expect that the low price is reflected in the service. TinyAmp S60 can be used also in the primary listening room, just the size of the room and speaker efficiency taken into account.</p>

<p>TinyAmp S60 has an outlet to power Squeezebox products. At the amplifier's back panel is a switch where you choose between 5V supply for Squeezebox Touch or Classic, or 9V to Squeezebox Receiver. Moreover it has 4 gold-plated banana plugs for connecting speaker cables. Sumoh TinyAmp S60 is built in aluminum and measures just approx. 150x150x40 mm.</p>

<h2>TinyAmp S60 Audio Performance Specifications</h2>

<pre><code>Power output, 4 Ω (10% THD+N)  65W
Power output, 4 Ω (0dBFS)  60W
Power output, 6 Ω (10% THD+N)  55W
Power output, 6 Ω (0dBFS)  50W
Power output, 8 Ω (10% THD+N)  40W
Power output, 8 Ω (0dBFS)  35W
Total hamornic distortion (-2.5dBFS, 8 Ω)  &lt;0.09 %
Dynamic Range, a-weighted   103 dB
Signal-to-noise ratio   103 dB
Channel separation  90 dB
Frequency response, audio range (20Hz - 20kHz)  +/-0.5dB
</code></pre>

<p>Squeezebox Touch is, of course, capable to play music from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_radio">Internet radio</a> stations and other online music services, like the rest of the products in the Squeezebox family. Squeezebox Touch can connect to <a href="http://facebook.com">Facebook</a>. You can view your Facebook page on the display and immediately send recommendations on exciting music you hear to your Facebook friends. Squeezebox Touch has an analog RCA output, a digital Toslink output and a digital coaxial output, just as there are mini-jack output for connecting headphones.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
