<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: GPG | x2q dot net]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/categories/gpg/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.x2q.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-10T17:15:39+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.x2q.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[x2q]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[x2q@x2q.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Howto Backup WD MyBook Live to Amazon S3 and Glacier]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/02/24/howto-backup-wd-mybook-live-to-amazon-s3-and-glacier/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T14:25:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/02/24/howto-backup-wd-mybook-live-to-amazon-s3-and-glacier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I helped a <a href="http://www.winniemethmann.com/">photographer</a> to backup a large photo collection (several
terabytes) from a <a href="http://www.wdc.com/">Western Digital (WD)</a> personal NAS
MyBook Live.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_Digital_My_Book">My Book Live Edition
NAS</a> was released by
Western Digital in 2011. They range in storage capacity from 1 to 4 TB. My Book
Live features a 1 GHz ARM processor, 256 MB of RAM, and 1000 Mbit/s ethernet
connectivity. Contrary to previous My Book Live versions it now features a
fully fledged <a href="http://www.debian.org/">Debian linux distribution</a>, whichs makes
the My Book Live easy to customize and adapt to different needs.</p>

<h2>Backup your My Book Live to Amazon S3 and Glacier</h2>

<p>This assumes that you got SSH access to your My Book Live. If you haven't got
SSH, then do the following to enable SSH access.</p>

<h3>Enable SSH via hidden menu on WD My Book Live</h3>

<p>Go to <a href="http://mybooklive/UI/ssh">http://mybooklive/UI/ssh</a> (case sensitive)
replace "mybooklive" if you have renamed your My Book Live to something else,
or replace it with its IP address. It's a hidden UI menu to enable SSH.</p>

<p>Now you are able to ssh to your My Book Live via
<a href="http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/">putty</a> or another ssh
client.</p>

<h3>Install the backup tool Duplicity etc.</h3>

<pre><code>  $ apt-get install python-boto duplicity util-linux trickle
</code></pre>

<p>I used the following Bash script as a cron job. The script features:</p>

<ul>
<li>exclusive locking using flock - ensures that only instance is actice at the time. This is useful, when your backup might run for several days.</li>
<li>bandwidth / upload limit using trickle.</li>
<li>custom temp and cache folders - this is required on a WD My Book Live as it got limited space on the root file system</li>
</ul>


<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/5024054.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code></code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Now it is time to make the script run every night. Edit your crontab:</p>

<pre><code>    $ crontab -e
</code></pre>

<p>Add the following line</p>

<pre><code>    # m h  dom mon dow   command 
    42  22  *   *   *    /root/wd-live-s3-backup.sh
</code></pre>

<p>Then be sure to check your log files and do restore to check that everything is
good.</p>

<h3>Adjust S3 lifecycle rule</h3>

<p>Amazon supports archiving of Amazon S3 Data to Amazon Glacier using lifecycle rules.</p>

<p>I use the following lifecycle rule for Amazon S3 and Glacier.</p>

<p><img src="http://lh3.ggpht.com/-9vxrov_LRmM/UXjf1037BII/AAAAAAAAKL4/tFJy90mQAjM/w677/s3-glacier-lifecycle-rules.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
