<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> <feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title><![CDATA[Category: PlayReady | x2q dot net]]></title><link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/categories/playready/atom.xml" rel="self"/><link href="http://www.x2q.net/"/> <updated>2013-03-03T13:35:16+01:00</updated> <id>http://www.x2q.net/</id> <author> <name><![CDATA[x2q]]></name> <email><![CDATA[x2q@x2q.net]]></email> </author> <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator> <entry><title type="html"><![CDATA[Howto run Netflix on Ubuntu Linux]]></title><link href="http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/02/23/howto-run-netflix-on-ubuntu-linux/"/> <updated>2013-02-23T22:52:00+01:00</updated> <id>http://www.x2q.net/blog/2013/02/23/howto-run-netflix-on-ubuntu-linux</id> <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Netflix is finally working on Linux - not native, but with a patched Wine build, you can now use Netflix under Linux.</p><p>For those who are not familiar with Netflix, it is an American provider of on-demand Internet streaming media available to both North and South America, the Caribbean, United Kingdom, Ireland, Sweden, Denmark, Norway, Finland.</p><h2>How to install</h2><pre><code>  $ sudo apt-add-repository ppa:ehoover/compholio
  $ sudo apt-get update
  $ sudo apt-get install netflix-desktop
</code></pre><p>The Netflix Desktop package installs all of the components necessary to run Netflix Watch Instantly under Wine, including the Windows version of Mozilla Firefox and Microsoft Silverlight v4. The package also includes some convience settings to integrate Netflix into Firefox in such a way that everything feels like a native application.</p><h2>Run Netflix</h2><p>You can launch the Netflix Desktop web app through desktop Dash menu. The Netflix Desktop application runs in full screen, but you can exit full screen mode by pressing F11 (just like any other browser).</p><h2>Use it for websites that require Silverlight / PlayReady DRM</h2><p>Start the Netflix Desktop web app and then press F11 (to exit full screen mode), then press ALT + v and then the menu occurs, now enable the Menu Bar and Navigation Toolbar.</p><p>Now you are able to navigate to <a href="http://web.sldrm.video.msn.com/">http://web.sldrm.video.msn.com/</a> or <a href="http://www.filmstriben.dk/">http://www.filmstriben.dk/</a>.</p> ]]></content> </entry> </feed>